# Elia Bellussi, MBA

Orbassano, Turin ITALY | +39 3336892117 | +44 7775701751

e.bellussi@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/eliabellussi/ | https://github.com/ebellussi

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Innovation manager with 10+ years of experience working in relationship and project management with stakeholders and clients such as the public sector, aerospace, telecommunication, and banking. Specialized in emerging technology, digital transformation, strategy and business development, and open innovation. Excellent organizational, communication, and presentation skills.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **EGI FOUNDATION** — Amsterdam, Netherlands

July 2022 – Present

### Senior Strategy and Innovation

- Developing and/or contributing to new project proposals and other partnership opportunities that support
  the EGI Federation strategy and contributing to the activities in projects within the assigned role(s),
  coordinating the participation of relevant EGI staff when in a lead role and ensuring successful delivery of
  results.
- Complying with the IMS processes and procedures and contributing to the conformity of the EGI Foundation to ISO 9000 and ISO 20000 standards and coordinating and delivering FitSM and ISO 27K training and related service offerings.
- Actively participating and promoting EGI and related activities at EGI Conferences and external events as well as (co-)authoring articles or other content to promote EGI and/or related activities.

### SAA – SCHOOL OF MANAGEMENT — Turin, Italy

Nov 2020 – Present

### **Contract Professor and Teacher Assistant**

- Teaching courses on "Digital Innovation and Organizational Change for Sustainability" and "Non-profit Digital Transformation".
- Overseeing case studies analysis for the Management Information Systems and Internal Control course.
- Guiding lectures with practical examples from business cases.

### **ALMAVIVA** — Turin, Italy

June 2020 – July 2022

### Innovation Manager

- Providing intellectual and methodological leadership in projects and proposals, coordinating teams in European calls for tenders, and focusing on excellence and impact.
- Contributing to the leadership and growth of the company through business analysis, by bringing fresh and innovative ideas, designing innovation processes, methodologies, and strategies, and implementing networks of partners and experts whom the company will be able to activate from day one to manage and deliver diverse projects as well as start-ups' scouting and evaluation.
- Introducing ideation of customized solutions for public administrations and the national healthcare system, being part of AlmavivA Future Technology Lab, and leading their digital transformation with a focus on artificial intelligence, especially on ethics, quantum computing, and high-performing computing.

## **CONSOFT SISTEMI** — Turin, Italy

May 2011 – June 2020

### **Corporate Business Solutions Manager**

- Heading the Big Data practice of the company, creating a cross-functional team, and developing the business plan and the company's strategy.
- Providing courses for 20 executives and employees with a focus on NoSQL for a branch of Lagrand Group.
- Training and tutoring colleagues on Big Data Analytics with a Hadoop infrastructure.

### Senior System Engineer

- Coordinated projects on continual service development through process design and analytics with a particular focus on KPIs and quality management for GE Avio Aero and Skylogic, a subsidiary of Eutelsat.
- Managed a tailored monitoring system related to the effectiveness of the company's infrastructure of 7.000 servers for Intesa Sanpaolo, as a product owner in an agile team.
- Contributing to developing and managing different projects/B2B products, in collaboration between the enterprise service desk and the enterprise projects development team for GE Avio Aero.

### **COMAU** — Rivalta di Turin, Italy

Feb 2017 – Feb 2017

### **Guest Lecturer**

- Conducting lectures for an Executive Master of Digital Innovation, collaborating with ESCP Business School.
- Trained and motivated a group of 30 executive students on coding and its impact on digital transformation.

### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE \_

# **VARIOUS INCUBATORS AND ACCELERATORS —** European Union

Nov 2020 - Present

## Startup Mentor

- Reorganising, redesigning, and strengthening business strategy, product development, and financial statements.
- Mentoring and training teams on design thinking, helping them to develop their business model and strategies.
- Supervising teams and providing support and information to be able to complete the assignments.

# **CLUB DIRIGENTI INFORMATICI** — Turin, Italy

March 2021 – Present

### **Board of Directors**

• Orchestrating events organisation from managing associated resources to executing the strategies.

### DIGITAL360 — Milan, Italy

Feb 2020 – Present

### **Contributing Writer**

• Authoring articles on Design Thinking, Data Strategy, and Scenario Planning published in Italian online magazines.

## EDUCATION \_\_

### Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence (MSc)

Expected 2023

Università Degli Studi di Turin — Turin, Italy

Natural Language Processing – Computer Vision – Multi-Agents System – AI Ethics.

### Master of Science in Disruptive Innovation (MDI)

Mar 2020

HULT International Business School — San Francisco, USA – GPA: 3.61 with Distinction

Design Thinking – System Thinking – Scenario Planning – Leading Digital Innovation – Co-Creation – Open Innovation.

### Master of Business Administration (MBA)

Aug 2019

HULT International Business School — London, UK – GPA: 3.26

Major in Project Management – Minor in Marketing & Sales – Campuses: London, Dubai, and Shanghai.

### Bachelor of Computer Science (BSc)

Oct 2011

Università Degli Studi di Turin — Turin, Italy

Artificial Intelligence and Multi-Agent System.

#### LANGUAGES

Italian (Native); English (Advanced); Spanish (Basic).

### SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Work Authorization: EU citizen.

**Certifications:** ITIL V3 Foundation, Foundations in Design Thinking (IDEO), Professional Scrum Master I (Scrum.org), FitSM Foundation.

**Affiliations:** IEEE (https://www.ieee.org). Club Dirigenti Informatici (http://www.clubdi.org/). AICA (http://www.aica.it/), Museo Piemontese dell'Informatica (http://www.mupin.it)

Elia Bellussi, 24/02/1981, Italian. I hereby authorize the use of my personal data in accordance to the GDPR 679/16